<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.olly.com/blogs/the-well.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.olly.com/blogs/the-well"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.olly.com/blogs/the-well.atom"/>
  <title>OLLY PBC - The Well</title>
  <updated>2025-02-19T07:06:45-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>OLLY PBC</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.olly.com/blogs/the-well/the-story-of-sleep-hygiene-and-sleep-quality</id>
    <published>2025-02-19T07:06:45-08:00</published>
    <updated>2025-02-19T07:06:48-08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.olly.com/blogs/the-well/the-story-of-sleep-hygiene-and-sleep-quality"/>
    <title>The Story of Sleep Hygiene and Sleep Quality</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shea Gonyo</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Is it time to give your sleep cycle a good scrub?</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.olly.com/blogs/the-well/the-story-of-sleep-hygiene-and-sleep-quality">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Sleep is more than a biological function—it's a necessity. So it’s understandably frustrating when sleep doesn’t come easy, or it feels like you spend more time tossing and turning instead of actually sleeping. But if it’s of any comfort, you’re hardly alone.</p>
[goods-inside]
<h2>According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), over a third of American adults are getting insufficient sleep (as of 2022).<sup>1</sup>
</h2>
<p>Now, there could be lots of reasons why you’re having trouble sleeping, but you don’t have to fall down a research spiral just yet. There are still some things you can do on your own, like practicing sleep hygiene and getting in tune with your circadian rhythm, to improve the quality of your sleep.</p>
<div style="text-align: left;" class="image-wrapper">
 <figure>
    <img style="float: none;" alt="Woman Sleeping" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0108/2900/4864/files/06-woman-sleeping.jpg?v=1738337517">
    <figcaption>Good sleep looks different for everyone. Bed hoggin’ sleep goblins unite!</figcaption>
 </figure>
</div>
<h3>Get Into (Circadian) Rhythm</h3>
<p>Circadian rhythms are the 24-hour cycles your body follows, running in the background to carry out functions like metabolism, body temperature and—you guessed it—sleep. Everyone has an internal rhythm, but it can be disrupted by factors like travel, stress, or work. So if you’re feeling jet lagged after traveling for work or pleasure, or you find yourself “off schedule” in the days (or weeks) before and after Daylight Savings change, it could be that you’re slightly off step with yourself.<sup>2</sup> Thankfully, even if you’re out of sync with this “master clock,” there’s ways to get back on time and even strengthen it.</p>
<h3>What’s sleep hygiene?</h3>
<p>Despite the word “hygiene,” sleep hygiene isn’t about cleanliness (although please, prioritize that too), but rather science-backed practices you can do to get a good night’s sleep.<sup>3</sup> While your circadian rhythm regulates more than your sleep cycle, a lot of good sleep hygiene comes down to reinforcing and supporting this biological rhythm.</p>
<div style="text-align: left;" class="image-wrapper mobile">
 <figure>
    <img style="float: none;" alt="Sleep Cycle Breakdown" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0108/2900/4864/files/06-sleep-cycle-mobile.jpg?v=1739234780">
    <figcaption>Good sleep begins long before bedtime. Check out these tips for optimal Zzz’s.</figcaption>
 </figure>
</div>
<div style="text-align: left;" class="image-wrapper desktop">
 <figure>
    <img style="float: none;" alt="Sleep Cycle Breakdown" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0108/2900/4864/files/06-sleep-cycle.jpg?v=1739234917">
    <figcaption>Good sleep begins long before bedtime. Check out these tips for optimal Zzz’s.</figcaption>
 </figure>
</div>
<h3>Let’s Start Tonight</h3>
<p>So now that you’ve gotten the very (very) brief 101 on sleep hygiene, here are a few practices you can start today (or tonight, or whenever you’re reading this) to improve your sleep hygiene and hopefully, your sleep. Remember to start gradually and try one thing at a time—starting small leads to bigger wins down the road.</p>
<div class="listing">
   <div class="indent-section">
		<h3 class="bullet">1. Give Yourself a Bedtime</h3>
		<p>Sorry not sorry. Adults need a set bedtime, too. Establishing a bedtime is the first piece of advice you’ll come across when you look up sleep hygiene. Sleeping and waking up at the same time every day (yes, even on weekends) calibrates your body’s internal clock, so you begin to develop a “sense” for when you’re about to rest and go to sleep.<sup>4</sup></p>
		<h3 class="bullet">2. Get Some Sunlight</h3>
<p>We see “go touch grass” and raise you “get some sunlight.” You might be wondering what the heck light has to do with catching Zzz’s, but light—both natural and artificial—is a huge influence on your circadian rhythm. Your body responds to light as it’s an indicator that it’s time to be awake. Exposure to natural daylight, especially in the morning, is shown to not only improve your sleep quality, but help you sleep longer (by up to 30 minutes).<sup>5</sup></p>
		<h3 class="bullet">3. Dim the Lights</h3>
<p>On the flip side, darkness is an internal indicator that it’s time to go to sleep. We understand you can’t just sit in complete darkness for hours before you actually go to bed, but you can switch to softer, dimmer lighting ahead of bedtime. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention recommends dimming everything two hours before your appointed bedtime to encourage your body to wind down and make it easier to drift off.<sup>6</sup></p>
<p>
		</p>
<h3 class="bullet">4. Screens are Bad Bed Chem</h3>
<p>Repeat after us: screens and sleep don’t mesh. When we said that artificial light affects your circadian rhythm, we also meant devices. The light from our phones, laptops, TVs, and tablets not only messes with your rhythm, but keeps you up—how many nights have you opened an app for a quick scroll, only to look up an hour later?<sup>7</sup> If you don’t want to physically leave your phone in another room, put your phone on Do Not Disturb and leave it face down on a surface that’s not your bed. We promise your notifications and DMs and texts will still be there in the morning.</p>
		<h3 class="bullet">5. Your Bed is for Sex and Sleep</h3>
<p>And since we’re on the topic of bed chem, keep your bed for bed-activities only. We want to further encourage the mental association between your bed and sleep. So that means no eating, non-sexual playing, scrolling or working in bed.<sup>8</sup></p>
<p>
	</p>
</div>
</div>
<h3>Need a little more help?</h3>
<p>Humans are creatures of habit, so we get it if some (or all) of these practices feel like a big change from your norm. If you find that adjusting to your new designated bedtime to be a drastic change, it might be helpful to try Melatonin.</p>
<p>If you’re new to sleep aids, don’t fret. We’ve outlined some OLLY sleep supplements by Melatonin dose per serving. All our sleep aids are also expertly formulated with L-Theanine, an amino acid that encourages relaxation*, and traditionally used botanical extracts from Chamomile, Passionflower and Lemon Balm.</p>
<div style="text-align: left;" class="image-wrapper">
 <figure>
    <img style="float: none;" alt="OLLY Sleep Collection" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0108/2900/4864/files/06-sleep-collection.jpg?v=1738337517">
    <figcaption>Which snooze will you choose? OLLY offers sleep supplements in a range of Melatonin mg’s.</figcaption>
 </figure>
</div>
<h3><a href="/products/sleep">Sleep Blackberry Zen</a></h3>
<p>Who doesn’t like a gummy? If you’re new to Melatonin, this is a tasty intro. Each yummy serving (2 gummies) contains 3 mg of Melatonin. Also comes in Strawberry Sunset flavor.</p>
<h3><a href="/products/extra-strength-sleep">Extra Strength Sleep</a></h3>
<p>If you’d like just a little more, try Extra Strength Sleep gummies, which contain 5 mg of Melatonin per 2 gummy serving.</p>
<h3><a href="/products/maximum-strength-sleep">Maximum Strength Sleep</a></h3>
<p>This is the most amount of Melatonin you’ll find in OLLY sleep gummies. Each 2 gummy serving comes with 10 mg of Melatonin in case your body prefers to dream in double digits.</p>
<h3><a href="/products/kids-sleep">Kids Sleep</a></h3>
<p>For kids 4 and up, OLLY Kids Sleep gummies are child-friendly with 0.5 mg of Melatonin per gummy for those occasional restless nights.</p>
<div style="text-align: left;" class="image-wrapper">
 <figure>
    <img style="float: none;" alt="OLLY Ultra Sleep Softgels" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0108/2900/4864/files/06-ultra-sleep.jpg?v=1738337517">
    <figcaption>OLLY Ultra Strength Softgels for those who need a little extra.</figcaption>
 </figure>
</div>
<h3>Bonus—<a href="/products/ultra-soft-gels-sleep">Ultra Strength Sleep Softgels</a>
</h3>
<p>Same expertly formulated sleep supplement, just in a soft gel. Ultra Strength Sleep is also 10 mg of Melatonin per 2 softgel serving as well as 150 mg of Magnesium, which helps to relax your muscles.</p>
<p>Adjusting your sleep habits are hard, but new habits can be formed. The best way to do so is to start small, stick to it and repeat, repeat, repeat. You’ve got this.</p>
<p>Happy snoozing.</p>
<div class="references">
<p>
<small><strong>References</strong></small>
<br>
<small><em>1 CDC. (2024, May 22). FastStats: Sleep in Adults. Sleep. <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/sleep/data-research/facts-stats/&lt;adults-sleep-facts-and-stats.html" target="_blank">https://www.cdc.gov/sleep/data-research/facts-stats/<adults-sleep-facts-and-stats.html class="visually-hidden"> - New Window</adults-sleep-facts-and-stats.html></a>
<br>
2 Bryan, L., &amp; Guo, L. (2023, September 8). What Is Circadian Rhythm? Sleep Foundation. <a href="https://www.sleepfoundation.org/circadian-rhythm" target="_blank">https://www.sleepfoundation.org/circadian-rhythm<span class="visually-hidden"> - New Window</span></a>
<br>
3 Suni, E. (2020, August 14). Mastering Sleep Hygiene: Your Path to Quality Sleep (D. Rosen, Ed.). Sleep Foundation. <a href="https://www.sleepfoundation.org/sleep-hygiene" target="_blank">https://www.sleepfoundation.org/sleep-hygiene<span class="visually-hidden"> - New Window</span></a>
<br>
4 Suni, E. (2020, August 14). Mastering Sleep Hygiene: Your Path to Quality Sleep (D. Rosen, Ed.). Sleep Foundation. <a href="https://www.sleepfoundation.org/sleep-hygiene" target="_blank">https://www.sleepfoundation.org/sleep-hygiene<span class="visually-hidden"> - New Window</span></a>
<br>
5 Blume, C., Garbazza, C., &amp; Spitschan, M. (2019). Effects of light on human circadian rhythms, sleep and mood. Somnology : Sleep Research and Sleep Medicine, 23(3), 147–156. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11818-019-00215-x" target="_blank">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11818-019-00215-x<span class="visually-hidden"> - New Window</span></a>
<br>
6 Effects of Light on Circadian Rhythms | NIOSH | CDC. (2023, April 13). Cdc.gov. <a href="https://archive.cdc.gov/www_cdc_gov/niosh/emres/longhourstraining/light.html" target="_blank">https://archive.cdc.gov/www_cdc_gov/niosh/emres/longhourstraining/light.html<span class="visually-hidden"> - New Window</span></a>
<br>
<em>7 Blume, C., Garbazza, C., &amp; Spitschan, M. (2019). Effects of light on human circadian rhythms, sleep and mood. Somnology : Sleep Research and Sleep Medicine, 23(3), 147–156. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11818-019-00215-x" target="_blank">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11818-019-00215-x<span class="visually-hidden"> - New Window</span></a>
<br>
8 Suni, E. (2020, August 14). Mastering Sleep Hygiene: Your Path to Quality Sleep (D. Rosen, Ed.). Sleep Foundation. <a href="https://www.sleepfoundation.org/sleep-hygiene" target="_blank">https://www.sleepfoundation.org/sleep-hygiene<span class="visually-hidden"> - New Window</span></a></em></em></small></p>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.olly.com/blogs/the-well/how-to-prioritize-your-mental-health-during-the-holidays</id>
    <published>2024-12-12T14:52:43-08:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-31T13:45:30-08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.olly.com/blogs/the-well/how-to-prioritize-your-mental-health-during-the-holidays"/>
    <title>How to Prioritize Your Mental Health During the Holidays</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shea Gonyo</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The good news: small steps can go a long way.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.olly.com/blogs/the-well/how-to-prioritize-your-mental-health-during-the-holidays">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The holiday season can be a lot—between family dynamics, holiday shopping, and keeping traditions alive, it’s easy to get caught up in the whirlwind. Being a dad and therapist doesn’t stop me from feeling the pressure like everyone else, and I want to share a few things to think about when it comes to taking care of your mental health this holiday season. You may not be able to eliminate stress, but here are a few things that might help.</p>
<p>[goods-inside]</p>
<div class="author-card">
<div class="author-image"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0108/2900/4864/files/kier-gaines_7829101d-d8ae-4574-82a5-0c352eb80385.jpg?v=1738359871" alt="Kier Gains" style="float: none;"></div>
<div class="author-bio">
<h3 class="about-author">About our Guest Author: Kier Gaines is a licensed therapist, speaker, father of two girls and renowned expert on nurturing mental health and self-wellness. He regularly shares insightful content across all his social media platforms. We’re thrilled to share some tangible tips for taking better care of yourself, from a real deal self-care expert.</h3>
</div>
</div>
<div class="listing">
<div class="indent-section">
<h3 class="bullet">1. Make Sleep a Priority (Especially During the Holidays)</h3>
<p>We all know how important sleep is for kids, but it’s just as important for us adults. It’s easy to get tempted to stay up late for that much needed “me time,” and sometimes, that’s okay. But you have to ask yourself, is staying up late actually making you feel better the next day? Sure, it might help you relax in the moment, but it can be too much of a tax to pay if you’re running on empty the next day.</p>
<p>And with holiday schedules being unpredictable, sticking to a strict routine might not always work. But if your kids usually go to bed at 8 and you can get them to bed by 9:30 during the holidays, that’s still a win. Just remember—go to bed with intention instead of passing out from exhaustion wherever you’re sitting. Try to stick as close to your routine as possible, even if it’s not perfect.</p>
<p>For those nights when sleep isn’t coming as easily as it usually does, <a href="/collections/sleep">OLLY offers a range of sleep supplements</a> for kids age 4+ and adults that might do the trick.</p>
<div class="image-wrapper" style="text-align: left;">
<figure><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0108/2900/4864/files/olly-sleep-products_b04f6b2c-fd99-4676-a2ea-30ce8492595c.jpg?v=1734477028" alt="OLLY Sleep Products" style="float: none;">
<figcaption>A few delightful sleep solutions in OLLY’s collection.</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<h3 class="bullet">2. Set Boundaries with Family</h3>
<p>Family can be great, but they can also test your limits in ways that no one else can. It’s easy to feel obligated to attend every event or engage in every conversation, sometimes the better thing to do is to step back. In this situation, you’re not required to participate in situations that drain you.</p>
<p>Instead of focusing on changing someone’s mind or viewpoint, spend that energy on the things that make you mentally safe. Sometimes, it’s about prioritizing what feels more peaceful.</p>
<h3 class="bullet">3. Take Breaks from Social Media</h3>
<p>Relax! I didn’t say to delete the app. It’s so easy to get sucked into scrolling through everyone else’s holiday highlights and start comparing your life to theirs. But let’s be real—social media is just a highlight reel designed to distract you.</p>
<p>If you’re finding it hard to put the phone down, try setting a timer or simply being mindful of how much time you’re spending on it. You don’t have to feel guilty for using social media, but it helps to be aware when it starts affecting how you feel about yourself and your holiday experience.</p>
<h3 class="bullet">4. Find Pockets of Time for Self-Care</h3>
<p>You may not get the hours of alone time you need during the holidays. In fact, you may find yourself asking, “How am I going to survive this?” It’s about finding those little pockets of time to recharge. Maybe that’s sneaking in a quiet cup of coffee before the house wakes up or taking a quick walk around the block to clear your head.</p>
<p>Think of it as refueling just enough to keep going. Nobody is able to run on a full tank all the time, but even a little can go a long way.</p>
<h3 class="bullet">5. You Have Permission to Say No</h3>
<p>You don’t have to say yes to everything. The holiday season can be full of invitations, events, and commitments, but you don’t need to do it all. Ask yourself: Do I really have the energy for this? Can I show up for this the way I want to?</p>
<div class="image-wrapper" style="text-align: left;">
<figure><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0108/2900/4864/files/woman-holding-coffee-mug_780e89c9-f9ad-45b5-8eb6-9e90efd54913.jpg?v=1738359871" alt="Woman holding coffee mug" style="float: none;">
<figcaption>Taking care of your mental health is key.</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p>If the answer is no, that’s okay. You’re allowed to protect your time and your energy. Think about how you can manage your commitments in a way that feels realistic, not overwhelming. It’s not about cutting everything out but being thoughtful about what you say yes to.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="reminder">
<h3 class="line-above">Remember:</h3>
<p>There’s no perfect formula for avoiding stress, but by giving yourself grace and paying attention to your mental health, you can get through it in a way that feels a little more manageable. Here’s to a more peaceful holiday season for you and yours.</p>
</div>
<div class="references">
<p><small><em>Kier Gaines is a paid partner of OLLY’s, who helped contribute to this article.</em></small></p>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.olly.com/blogs/the-well/don-t-fall-for-these-4-gut-health-myths</id>
    <published>2024-10-11T12:10:39-07:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-31T13:35:43-08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.olly.com/blogs/the-well/don-t-fall-for-these-4-gut-health-myths"/>
    <title>Don’t Fall for These 4 Gut Health Myths</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shea Gonyo</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>There’s no shortage of info out there, including <br class="desktop">the not-so-true kind. Plus, a guide about poop!</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.olly.com/blogs/the-well/don-t-fall-for-these-4-gut-health-myths">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Here at OLLY, we take gut health seriously. And with good reason: a healthy gut is essential for overall health and well-being. We believe caring for your digestion and gut proactively—as opposed to reactive over the counter solutions—is a crucial part of everyday wellness.</p>
[goods-inside]
<h2>Gut health is also a complex issue brimming with misunderstandings.</h2>
<p>So if you’ve gotten a mixed message or two about things you should or shouldn’t do to support your digestive health, you’re not alone. The good news: we’re here to help by breaking down four common myths.</p>
<div class="listing">
	<div class="indent-section">
		<h3 class="bullet">Myth #1: Daily Bowel Movements are a Must</h3>
		<p>69% of Americans believe you need to poop daily.<sup>1</sup> The real deal: healthy poops have a lot to do with consistency—not too hard, not too soft—and not just frequency.</p>
		<p class="mb-0"><strong>The Bristol Stool Chart is often used to measure stool quality from 1-7</strong></p>
		<ul class="tight">
			<li>Type 1-2 is considered constipation, as the poops are difficult to pass</li>
			<li>Type 3-4 is considered healthy, as they are easy to pass</li>
			<li>Type 5-7 is considered fast motility, resulting in watery stools</li>
		</ul>
		<div class="image-wrapper" style="text-align: left;">
			<figure><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0108/2900/4864/files/poops.svg?v=1728592269" alt="Poops" style="float: none;">
			<figcaption>Everyone has unique bowels and it’s typical for stools to vary based on a number of diet and lifestyle factors. If you’re experiencing too-loose or too-hard stools on the regular, share this with your healthcare provider.</figcaption>
			</figure>
		</div>
		<p>If your poop is “just right”, it’s a sign your gut is in balance. This means you have a healthy mix of bacteria and probiotics that support optimal transit time and reduced inflammation.<sup>2</sup></p>
		<p class="mb-0"><strong>Looking to get your stools on track? Try these bowel-balancing tips:</strong></p>
		<ul class="tight">
			<li>Eat fiber-rich foods (aka fruits and veggies) to help move things along<sup>3</sup>
</li>
			<li>Drink plenty of water to keep poops soft and easy to pass<sup>3</sup>
</li>
			<li>Try a supplement with probiotics to support your gut microbiome, like <a href="/products/probiotic-tropical-mango">OLLY Tropical Mango Probiotic gummies</a>*</li>
		</ul>
		<h4 class="line-above">The bottom line:</h4>
		<p>Gut health is often shown in poop consistency, not just frequency.</p>
		<h3 class="bullet">Myth #2: Juice Cleanses are Good for Your Gut</h3>
		<p>Half of the American population are drawn to juice cleanses, either having tried, currently trying or wanting to try one.<sup>1</sup> This type of diet, which involves consuming only juices from vegetables and fruits, is often framed as a quick fix. Easy to follow that logic, right? How could lots of fruits and veggie juice not be good for you? The reality: gut health is complex and there isn’t a simple shortcut.</p>
		<p>Your body already has a natural detox system, like your liver, kidneys and GI tract.<sup>4</sup> Juice cleanses can lead to nutrient imbalances, and they tend to lack fiber which is key for a healthy gut.<sup>4</sup> Another factor: it’s important to have a balance of good bacteria in the gut, which can get neglected without a balanced diet.</p>
		<h4 class="line-above">The bottom line:</h4>
		<p>Skip the cleanse and opt for a balanced diet that includes fruits and veggies.</p>
		<h3 class="bullet">Myth #3: Gut Health Issues Stay in Your Gut</h3>
		<p>Only about half of Americans are aware that poor sleep can be a sign of an unhealthy gut.<sup>1</sup> The importance of the gut/brain connection is something scientists are continuing to learn about, but we know that the two have a special relationship. And when the connection is out of whack, it can affect various aspects of our health.</p>
		<div class="image-wrapper" style="text-align: left;">
			<figure><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0108/2900/4864/files/woman-sleeping.jpg?v=1728592274" alt="Woman Sleeping" style="float: none;">
			<figcaption>Many people don't realize there's a connection between sleep and gut health.</figcaption>
			</figure>
		</div>
		<p class="mb-0"><strong>Ways this shows up:</strong></p>
		<ul class="tight">
			<li>The Vagus nerve connects the gut and brain, helping to manage stress—any gut issues can disrupt this<sup>5</sup>
</li>
			<li>The gut produces chemicals sent to your brain that affect mood and emotions, like serotonin and GABA<sup>5</sup>
</li>
			<li>The gut (which houses 70-80% of your immune system) protects mental health by preventing toxins from entering the bloodstream<sup>5</sup>
</li>
		</ul>
		<h4 class="line-above">The bottom line:</h4>
		<p>Taking care of your gut goes way beyond the belly.</p>
		<h3 class="bullet">Myth #4: Supplements are a Quick Fix for a Healthy Gut</h3>
		<p>Gut health supplements aren’t a magical shortcut, but they’re like your BFF ready to support you along your health journey. The best approach: focus on building healthy daily habits for long-term results. For example, think of Probiotics like the new multivitamin—the thing everyone does every day without thinking too hard about it.</p>
		<p class="mb-0"><strong>More ways to support your gut health on the daily:</strong></p>
		<ul class="tight">
			<li>Manage stress with yoga, meditation and reflection<sup>6</sup>
</li>
			<li>Eat smaller, more frequent meals to avoid overwhelming your gut<sup>6</sup>
</li>
			<li><a href="/products/probiotic-tropical-mango">Try OLLY Probiotic + Prebiotic gut health gummies</a></li>
		</ul>
		<h4 class="line-above">The bottom line:</h4>
		<p>It’s all about bite-sized daily habits.</p>
	</div>
</div>
<p>When it comes to health advice, there’s a lot of information out there. Don’t believe everything you see on social media. It’s always a good idea to do your research and seek out peer-reviewed or scientifically backed articles. Here’s to delightful digestion!</p>
<div class="references">
<p><small><strong>References:</strong></small><br><small><em><sup>1</sup>Kellman, R. (2014). The microbiome diet: The scientifically proven way to restore your gut health and achieve permanent weight loss. Da capo Lifelong Books.</em></small></p>
<p><small><em><sup>2</sup>  Tuohy, Kieran M., et al. "Using probiotics and prebiotics to improve gut health." Drug discovery today 8.15 (2003): 692-700.</em></small></p>
<p><small><em><sup>3</sup> MDVIP/Ipsos. (2023). Findings of study: Results of a MDVIP/Ipsos poll conducted between Marsh 28-29, 2023. [Data file]. Retrieved from <a href="https://www.ipsos.com/sites/default/files/ct/news/documents/2023-05/MDVIP%20-%20Gut%20Health%20Key%20Findings%20May%202023_0.pdf" target="_blank">https://www.ipsos.com/sites/default/files/ct/news/documents/2023-05/MDVIP%20-%20Gut%20Health%20Key%20Findings%20May%202023_0.pdf<span class="visually-hidden"> - new window</span></a></em></small></p>
<p><small><em><sup>4</sup> Smith, J. (2020). The importance of gut health. Journal of Nutrition and Wellness, 10(2), 1-10.</em></small></p>
<p><small><em><sup>5</sup> Gundersen Health System. (n.d.). Gut health 101: Is your poop normal? Retrieved from <a href="https://www.gundersenhealth.org/health-wellness/staying-healthy/gut-health-101-is-your-poop-normal" target="_blank">https://www.gundersenhealth.org/health-wellness/staying-healthy/gut-health-101-is-your-poop-normal<span class="visually-hidden"> - new window</span></a></em></small></p>
<p><small><em><sup>6</sup> Live Science. (2015, June 17). Juice cleanses: Fact or fiction? <a href="https://www.livescience.com/48941-juice-cleanses-fact-fiction.html" target="_blank">https://www.livescience.com/48941-juice-cleanses-fact-fiction.html<span class="visually-hidden"> - new window</span></a></em></small></p>
<p><small><em><sup>7</sup> Healthline. (n.d.). Signs of an Unhealthy Gut and What to Do About it. Retrieved from <a href="https://www.healthline.com/health/gut-health" target="_blank">https://www.healthline.com/health/gut-health<span class="visually-hidden"> - new window</span></a></em></small></p>
<p><small><em><sup>8</sup> Healthline. (n.d.). The gut-brain connection: How gut health affects mental health. Retrieved from <a href="https://www.healthline.com/nutrition/gut-brain-connection" target="_blank">https://www.healthline.com/nutrition/gut-brain-connection<span class="visually-hidden"> - new window</span></a></em></small></p>
<p><small><em><sup>9</sup> MDVIP. (2023). Most Americans are uninformed about gut health and the microbiome. Ipsos. <a href="https://www.ipsos.com/en-us/most-americans-are-uninformed-about-gut-health-and-microbiome" target="_blank">https://www.ipsos.com/en-us/most-americans-are-uninformed-about-gut-health-and-microbiome<span class="visually-hidden"> - new window</span></a></em></small></p>
<p><small><em><sup>10</sup> Piedmont Healthcare. (n.d.). 10 tips for a healthier gut. Retrieved from <a href="https://www.piedmont.org/living-real-change/10-tips-for-a-healthier-gut" target="_blank">https://www.piedmont.org/living-real-change/10-tips-for-a-healthier-gut<span class="visually-hidden"> - new window</span></a></em></small></p>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.olly.com/blogs/the-well/lets-talk-about-menopause</id>
    <published>2024-09-23T18:15:02-07:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-31T13:36:13-08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.olly.com/blogs/the-well/lets-talk-about-menopause"/>
    <title>Let’s Talk About Menopause</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shea Gonyo</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Because we’re all underestimating how big of a deal it is.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.olly.com/blogs/the-well/lets-talk-about-menopause">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[	<p>Hot flashes. Mood swings. Whole body sweats. Fatigue.</p>
	<p>We tiptoe around the topic, make some jokes here and there, but we don’t really talk about menopause. We even refer to it in a hush-hush euphemism—“the change.”</p>
	[goods-inside]
	<h2>Only 28% (of women) knew what to expect before starting menopause...</h2>
	<p>A recent U.S. Women’s Wellness Report found that of the women surveyed, only 28% knew what to expect before starting menopause, and that 61% of menopausal women did not talk about their experience with others.<sup>1</sup></p>
	<p>We get it. Menopause isn’t exactly a pleasant, or casual, conversation topic. So maybe we’re trying to ignore it into not existing. Maybe we’re carrying some misplaced shame and stigma about this big change. Or maybe we didn’t want to think about it because it’d trigger a late-night doom scroll about the horrors of aging and menopause and our own fleeting mortality—and we already have so much on our plate.</p>
	<p>But the thing is, maybe if we talked about it, menopause wouldn’t be so scary. And then we’d all be better prepared when it happens to us, which is something OLLY CEO Hanneke Willenborg wished for when she started menopause.</p>
	<div style="text-align: left;" class="image-wrapper">
		<figure>
			<img style="float: none;" alt="“I think we're underestimating
how big of a deal [menopause] is.”" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0108/2900/4864/files/02-ceo-quote.jpg?v=1727137887">
			<figcaption>Hanneke Willenborg, OLLY CEO</figcaption>
		</figure>
	</div>
	<blockquote>
	<p>“In most of my friend groups I’m the youngest, so they’ve already been going through this,” she said. “And I remember calling them once I started to get symptoms like ‘why didn’t you tell me?!’” Her surprise didn’t end there.</p>
	<p>“I literally feel that I have to go through puberty all over again” she said before sharing some of her “more difficult” symptoms. “It’s a big deal and I think we’re underestimating how big of a deal it is.”</p>
	</blockquote>
	<p>Menopause does seem like a pretty big, scary deal, but you’re not alone. Literally and figuratively.</p>
	<h3>A Growing but Unaddressed Need</h3>
	<p>According to 2017 U.S. Census projections<sup>2</sup>, by 2030, the median age in the U.S. will be 40, with women between the ages of 40 to 64 outnumbering women under 18. The North American Menopause Society also estimates that by 2025, 1.1 billion women worldwide will be postmenopausal<sup>3</sup>.</p>
	<p>TLDR? The population of menopausal and postmenopausal people is growing. But despite this increasing need, awareness and access to menopause relief can’t quite keep up.</p>
	<p>“If you look at products out there right now, women’s health has been very underrepresented and very simplified,” said Punam Patel, VP of Product, who explained that women’s health can be broadly generalized in three life stages: young age, reproductive age and menopause. “Products usually are focused on reproductive health or general health. But it’s a lot more complex than that.”</p>
	<p>Willenborg agrees. “I started looking up menopausal products and what’s available in the market is either for hot flashes or vaginal dryness, but there’s no holistic solution for pre-menopausal or menopausal women.”</p>
	<p>So OLLY made one.</p>
	<div style="text-align: left;" class="image-wrapper">
		<figure>
			<img style="float: none;" alt="“I think we're underestimating
how big of a deal [menopause] is.”" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0108/2900/4864/files/03-menopause-product.jpg?v=1727137887">
			<figcaption>Mellow Menopause™ is expertly formulated and made by women who get it.</figcaption>
		</figure>
	</div>
	<h3>A Real Solution for a Major Life Change</h3>
	<p><a href="/products/mellow-menopause">Mellow Menopause™</a> is OLLY’s way of supporting women who’re at a life stage that can be—let's be real—confusing and downright uncomfortable at times. But whether you were prepared for menopause or not, you don’t have to tough it out.</p> 
	<p>All of our products are science backed, benefit driven and easy to understand, but we’re especially proud that that Mellow Menopause™ is also our first clinically studied supplement.</p>
	<p>“Menopause affects 100% of women who live to the age of impact<sup>4</sup>,” said Shikha Snigdha, Senior Scientific Affairs Director, “and yet it remains an under-researched and under-funded area of focus.”</p>
	<p>“Knowing that a product has undergone a clinical study helps consumers make informed decisions about their health and allows them to put their trust and confidence in the product they’re choosing.”</p>
	<p>During our study, women reported hot flash relief within 24 hours of starting Mellow Menopause™ and with continued use, got relief from mood swings (including feelings of anxiety and stress) and menopause-associated headaches. Continual use also reduced night sweats and hot flashes, as well as helped manage fatigue, improve sleep quality and even supporting healthy sexual interest.</p>
	<p>That’s pretty confidence-boosting.</p>
	<div class="listing">
		<div class="indent-section">
			<h3 class="decoration bullet">Support for 11 Menopause Symptoms*</h3>
			<p><strong>What also boosts our confidence is knowing that Mellow Menopause™ supports not one, but 11 menopause symptoms:</strong></p>
			<div class="row col-2">
				<ul class="col small">
					<li>Hot flashes*</li>
					<li>Night sweats*</li>
					<li>Sleep*</li>
					<li>Nervousness*</li>
					<li>Mood*</li>
					<li>Irritability*</li>
				</ul>
				<ul class="col small">
					<li>Physical fatigue*</li>
					<li>Vaginal dryness*</li>
					<li>Mental exhaustion*</li>
					<li>Healthy sexual interest*</li>
					<li>And occasional headaches associated with menopause*</li>
				<ul>
			</ul>
</ul>
</div>
		</div>
		<div class="indent-section">
			<h3 class="decoration bullet">Ingredients</h3>
			<p><strong>Each certified vegan, gluten-free capsule contains:</strong></p>
			<p><strong>EstroG-100®</strong> <br>
			The muscle behind Mellow Menopause™ that helps provides relief from all the fun stuff your body will throw at you.* Each serving contains a clinically studied dose of EstroG-100®, a proprietary blend made of three beneficial root extracts traditionally used in Korean and Chinese folk medicine: <em>Angelica gigas, Cynanchum wilfordii and Phlomis umbrosa</em>.</p>
			<p><strong>GABA</strong> <br>
			This amino acid is here for stress support. GABA starts working within 60 minutes to support mental relaxation and help counter the acute effects of stress.* Handy, right?</p>
		</div>
		<div class="indent-section">
			<h3 class="decoration bullet">Expertly Formulated</h3>
			<p><strong>Mellow Menopause™ is:</strong></p>
			<div class="row col-2">
				<ul class="col small">
					<li>Hormone-free</li>
					<li>Estrogen-free</li>
					<li>Soy-free</li>
				</ul>
				<ul class="col small">
					<li>Drug-free</li>
					<li>Gluten-free </li>
					<li>Certified vegan</li>
				<ul>
		</ul>
</ul>
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<p>All in all, impressive.</p>
<h3>Support Beyond Supplements</h3>
<p>OLLY’s out to make menopause a bit more manageable, and we’re not stopping at just simple and accessible supplements—we're also launching a new menopause policy this fall so that Ollies can continue to show up as their authentic selves.</p>
<p>Our menopause policy, which was reviewed by OLLY partner Dr. Kiarra King, OBGYN, aims to normalize menopause and lay down a support system at work so that people can access accommodations and resources while continuing to perform their best.</p>
<p>The policy will be available to all OLLY employees, regardless of gender, who are going through menopause or supporting someone who is.</p>
<p>Currently, 70% of OLLY’s workforce is made up of women who’re at all different ages and life stages. So just as we already offer pregnancy and maternity leave policies to provide the real and meaningful support, a menopause policy just made a lot of sense.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Pre-menopause brain fog is real,” Willenborg said. “And it’s okay that sometimes somebody needs a time out, or walks away, or takes a step back. All these things are going to make a very supportive workplace.”</p>
<p>“I feel really good about what we’re doing, not only to support women at OLLY, but also the product that we provide with real solutions for the women that we serve.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>At OLLY, we take higher standards seriously and that begins from within. So keep checking back periodically to see how we’re doing. And remember, navigating your menopause journey can be super overwhelming, but you’re not alone. Learn more and join the convo on our Instagram.</p>
<div class="references">
<p><small><strong>References:</strong></small><br><small><em><sup>1</sup> Cameron, Lindsey (2024, Jan 30). Women’s Wellness – US – 2024. Mintel womens-wellness-us-2024</em></small></p>
<p><small><em><sup>2</sup> Bureau, U. C. (2017). 2017 National Population Projections Tables: Main Series. The United States Census Bureau. <a href="https://www.census.gov/data/tables/2017/demo/popproj/2017-summary-tables.html" target="_blank">https://www.census.gov/data/tables/2017/demo/popproj/2017-summary-tables.html<span class="visually-hidden"> - new window</span></a></em></small></p>
<p><small><em><sup>3</sup> Petridis, E. (n.d.). <a href="https://www.menopause.org/docs/default-source/press-release/late-reproductive-stage-symptoms-vs-menopause.pdf" target="_blank">https://www.menopause.org/docs/default-source/press-release/late-reproductive-stage-symptoms-vs-menopause.pdf<span class="visually-hidden"> - new window</span></a></em></small></p>
<p><small><em><sup>4</sup> Aninye, I. O., Laitner, M. H., &amp; Chinnappan, S. (2021). Menopause preparedness: perspectives for patient, provider, and policymaker consideration. Menopause, 28(10), 1186–1191. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/gme.0000000000001819" target="_blank">https://doi.org/10.1097/gme.0000000000001819<span class="visually-hidden"> - new window</span></a> </em></small></p>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.olly.com/blogs/the-well/read-our-social-impact-report-card</id>
    <published>2024-06-20T10:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2025-01-31T13:34:50-08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.olly.com/blogs/the-well/read-our-social-impact-report-card"/>
    <title>Read Our Social Impact Report Card</title>
    <author>
      <name>Shea Gonyo</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>A peek inside the full report of OLLY’s impact internally and externally.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.olly.com/blogs/the-well/read-our-social-impact-report-card">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>We’re more than a supplement brand. We’re a company devoted to using our business for good. At OLLY, we believe that you can’t be well if you can’t be real. And being real starts with transparency—openly sharing the impact our business has on peoples’ lives and on this great big planet we all share. Keep scrolling to read the receipts on how we’re doing with all that.</p>
[goods-inside]
<h2>OLLY has been a BCorp since 2017... because we take this higher standard quite seriously.</h2>
<p>In case you’re new here, OLLY has been a BCorp since 2017 and we’ve been working tirelessly over the past 18 months to on our 3rd round of recertification of our BCorp status, because we take this higher standard quite seriously. (What can we say, we love a challenge.) We’re proud to report we’re trending in the right direction, only improving our scores year over year and learning (oh so much) as we go.</p>
<div class="image-wrapper" style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0108/2900/4864/files/01-social-impact-report-card_72413afa-7494-4890-8e32-12887ccd2554.jpg?v=1728675527" alt="Happy people" style="float: none;"></div>
<div class="listing">
<h3 class="bullet">What you’ll find in these reports:</h3>
<h4>A deep dive into our company’s purpose</h4>
<ul>
<li>We exist to make wellness accessible &amp; delightful. That means more than physical health.</li>
</ul>
<h4>How we take care of our employees (beyond salaries and benefits)</h4>
<ul>
<li>We’re focused on five key aspects of employee culture and wellbeing: Engagement, Recognition, Belonging, Safety and Autonomy.</li>
</ul>
<h4>How our employees help take care of our communities </h4>
<ul>
<li>Volunteering is key to OLLY’s culture and we’re intentional about making space for OLLY employees to make a hands-on difference.</li>
</ul>
<h4>How our social mission partners are putting our donations to use</h4>
<ul>
<li>Learn more about our key partnerships with The Loveland Foundation, Walmart, and more.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Our path to a smaller corporate footprint</h4>
<ul>
<li>We don’t play around with the role we play in reducing our impact on the planet. We’re aspiring to innovate and lead the change we hope to see.</li>
</ul>
<h4>And more!</h4>
</div>
<p>Seriously, this is a good read.</p>
<p><a href="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0108/2900/4864/files/2023_OLLY_Social_Impact_Report.pdf?v=1724947966" title="Click here to open our 2023 Social Impact Report." class="decoration" target="_blank">Click here to open our 2023 Social Impact Report.</a></p>
<p><span>This is, by no means, the end of the story. We have lofty goals for 2024, 2025 and beyond, (including a roadmap to emissions reductions by 2030). Keep checking back for more details on our social impact goals, coming to a blog near you (right here) soon. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
